Now that you've listened and answered all the answers.
questions, let's move to step 6, check the
Let's examine some common mistakes that students frequently
make in our sample exercise from the previous video.
In this exercise, students often struggle with blank 6, 7 and 8.
The correct answer for blank 6 is 18
,000 years, however, the answers provided by the
students can vary a lot.
It's unnecessary to write the word all, because
it's already in the note.
You also need to pay attention to commas and periods.
They are used to separate thousands in decimals,
which many of you are not aware of.
For blank 7, the correct answer is powder.
Many students made mistakes in this question, which
is due to spelling mistakes or not knowing
the word.
For blank 8, the correct answer is bush honey.
This is the answer that we need to base on
its pronunciation.
So what are the reasons for these mistakes?
The first one is due to carelessness.
In the exercise about Indigenous Australian R, if
the student is not careful, they might make
many spelling mistakes.
For example, storytelling.
The correct way of spelling the word is
without space between story and telling.
Or they might write the phrase musical instruments
without the plural form.
Another reason is that students don't check the answers carefully.
You need to compare your answers with the
predictions to correct the grammatical mistakes.
The third reason is due to lack of vocabulary.
Some words, you have to predict them based on
their pronunciation.
For example, the word bush honey.
It cannot be push honey.
The last one is because you are misled
by distractors.
To boost your listening skills, you have to
expand your vocabulary.
For example, in the first exercise about Indigenous
Australian R, after listening, you should compile the
words from the listening section to make a
list of topic rated words and learn them like this.
Another thing you should remember is that you
need to make predictions before listening.
Because this can provide you with all the
clues that help you listen in an attentive and active way.
Predicting helps us make wiser decisions.
Next, you will practice these skills with more
note completion exercises.
Remember the steps you've learned and get ready to listen actively.